A Guide to the Papers of the National Association of Pediatric Nurse Practitioners, 1972-1992
Claude Moore Health Sciences Library
- SERIES 1: Administrative Office Documents
  - Subseries: - Correspondence and Related Documents
    - McNeil Scholarship and Travel Grant January - December 1985 (Box-folder 008-002)
      Re: NAPNAP Scholarship and travel grant winners
    - NAPNAP Seal of Acceptance November - December 1985 (Box-folder 008-003)
      Re: Philosophy of NAPNAP seal of endorsement/acceptance, application to Proctor & Gamble pampers, protocol
    - Past President, Rudy, C.: Correspondence March 3; December 31, 1986 (Box-folder 008-004)
      Re: NAPNAP promotional material, financial report
    - Dickerson, M. to Jonides et al. February 3, 1987 (Box-folder 008-005)
      Re: Henry Silver Award Nominees
    - Continuing Education Committee June 1987 (Box-folder 008-006)
      Re: Report to Council on the continuing education unit
    - Committees and Executive Office 1986 - 1987 (Box-folder 008-007)
      Re: Assessment of nurse practice acts, NAPNAP office use of computers, board, staff, committee members, committee goals, members, mission of long-range planning committee
    - Financial April 30, 1987 (Box-folder 008-008)
      Re: 3rd quarter financial report
    - Wiener Group to McGuire, M. September - October 1987 (Box-folder 008-009)
      Re: Cooperation on brochure to promote saline nasal drops
    - Capitol Association about Nursing Shortage October 1987 (Box-folder 008-010)
      Re: Sending ANA paper on nursing shortage, Capitol Associates literature on the company
    - Journal of Pediatric Health Care August 1986 - October 1988 (Box-folder 008-011)
      Re: Correspondence, minutes of NAPNAP journal advisory board
    - Executive Office Staff, Committee Members 1988 (Box-folder 008-012)
      Re: Officers and committee members
    - McGuire, M: Correspondence February - December 1988 (Box-folder 008-013)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in domestic violence awareness, seal of approval for Mennen Baby Bath
    - Miscellaneous Correspondence, NAPNAP Wiener project April - December 1988 (Box-folder 008-014)
      Re: Production of brochure "Baby's First Cold" to promote Winthrop Products nasal drops
    - Miscellaneous: Nursing shortage January - October 1988 (Box-folder 008-015)
      Re: NAPNAP statement to Senate Appropriations Committee, NAPNAP participation in NFSNO statement on nursing shortage
    - NAPNAP & Edelman about Child Care Campaign May - November 1988 (Box-folder 008-016)
      Re: Collaborative promotional campaign for Lysol products for childcare
    - NAPNAP PNP Universe Study 1988 (Box-folder 008-017)
      Re: Planning funding, execution of PNP Universe study
    - NAPNAP PNP Universe Study December 1988 (Box-folder 008-018)
      Re: PNP Universe study report
    - NAPNAP Membership Survey 1988 (Box-folder 008-019)
      Re: Blank survey form, summary of results
    - Capitol Associates to McGuire, M. & Richardson, B. February - August 1988 (Box-folder 008-020)
      Re: Various reports and articles on nursing shortage, including AMA report, reports on secretary's Commission on Nursing, reports on Armed Forces pay, reports on Nurse Education Reauthorization Act, report to Congress about nurse practitioners
    - Continuing Education Committee June - September 1988 (Box-folder 008-021)
      Re: NAPNAP guide for organizing and evaluation CEU programs, continuing education report
    - Long Range Planning Committee June - October 1988 (Box-folder 008-022)
      Re: Meeting minutes, action plan
    - President Millonig, V: Correspondence June - August 1989 (Box-folder 008-023)
      Re: Executive board members, chapter visits, Safe Kids campaign participation, NAPNAP position on infant formula, support of Medicaid PNP reimbursement, International Food Information Council
    - Millonig, V: Correspondence September - October 1989 (Box-folder 008-024)
      Re: NAPNAP lobbyist, legislation, miscellaneous business
    - Millonig, V: Correspondence November - December 1989 (Box-folder 008-025)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, including: NAPNAP endorsements, position on breast feeding
    - President Elect, Mullins, R.: Correspondence July 1989-February 1990 (Box-folder 009-001)
      Re: Miscellaneous NAPNAP business, bylaws
    - Executive Director, McGuire, M.: Correspondence April 14, 1989 - August 3, 1989 (Box-folder 009-002)
      Re: Insurance
    - McGuire, M: Correspondence and Related Documents June - August 1989 (Box-folder 009-003)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, National Safe Kids Campaign, corporate relations, nurse practice acts
    - McGuire, M.: Correspondence September 6 - 19, 1989 (Box-folder 009-004)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, corporate support
    - McGuire, M: Correspondence October 13 - 30, 1989 (Box-folder 009-005)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, review of universe study and membership study, corporate support
    - McGuire, M.: Correspondence November 14 - 17, 1989 (Box-folder 009-006)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, NAPNAP seal of acceptance for Pampers, 1987-1988 Pam-pers publications with ads featuring NAPNAP seal
    - McGuire, M.: Correspondence December 8 - 29, 1989 (Box-folder 009-007)
      Re: Seal of acceptance, corporate support
    - Director of Membership and Communications: Correspondence May - December 1989 (Box-folder 009-008)
      Re: PR, membership, use of NAPNAP mailing labels, newsletter issues, chapters, expert witness
    - Continuing Education Committee, Membership Committee January - December 1989 (Box-folder 009-009)
      Re: Form letters to members about renewal, joining conference, food council, member-ship statistics 1989 - 1990, Henry Silver Award, continuing education program report
    - Executive Secretary: Correspondence August - November 1989 (Box-folder 009-010)
      Re: Miscellaneous NAPNAP business
    - National Office Manager: Correspondence June - December 1989 (Box-folder 009-011)
      Re: Mailing list use, chapters, NAPNAP officers' duties, long range plan, Universe study, NAPNAP policy statements
    - Brochure and Bylaw Committees Correspondence July - November 1989 (Box-folder 009-012)
      Re: By-law changes, NAPNAP brochures
    - Nominations Committee Correspondence April - November 1989 (Box-folder 009-013)
      Re: Nominations and elections
    - Legislative Committee Correspondence July - December 1989 (Box-folder 009-014)
      Re: Miscellaneous legislative issues, including member letters to Senators supporting coverage of NP services
    - Long Range Planning Committee March - October 1989 (Box-folder 009-015)
      Re: Meeting minutes and planning, discussion of Universe study, development of three-year strategy and initiatives, assignment of initiatives to comittees
    - Children's Television Task Force September 1, 1989 (Box-folder 009-016)
      Re: Children's television issues
    - Lists: Executive Board, Staff, Committees 1989 (Box-folder 009-017)
      Re: Board members, staff, committee members
    - Journal of Pediatric Health Care March - October 1989 (Box-folder 009-018)
      Re: Journal Advisory Board Members
    - NAPNAP/ McNeil Scholarship & NAPNAP Grant-In-Aid October - December 1989 (Box-folder 010-001)
      Re: Application information, 1989 winners of scholarships, travel grants
    - Universe Study January - June 1989 (Box-folder 010-002)
      Re: Includes executive summary of Universe Study
    - NAPNAP Annual Conference May - December 1989 (Box-folder 010-003)
      Re: Conference contest
    - McGuire Woods/ NAPNAP, Johnsen vs. School District, amicus brief June - December 1989 (Box-folder 010-004)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in amicus curiae in school nurse case
    - NAPNAP Position on Domestic Violence February - April 1989 (Box-folder 010-005)
      Re: includes policy statement draft
    - Edelman - NAPNAP Childcare Campaign January - June 1989 (Box-folder 010-006)
      Re: Collaborative promotional campaign for Lysol
    - NAPNAP - Wiener Company Project January - June 1989 (Box-folder 010-007)
      Re: Brochure "Baby's First Cold" to promote Winthrop Nasal Drops
    - NAPNAP - Johnson & Johnson Correspondence August 3 - 11, 1989 (Box-folder 010-008)
      Re: Refusal of NAPNAP seal of approval for education video tapes
    - NAPNAP - Mennen Project July - December 1989 (Box-folder 010-009)
      Re: NAPNAP seal of approval for Mennen Baby Magic
    - NAPNAP - Proctor & Gamble Funding June - October 1989 (Box-folder 010-010)
      Re: P&G grant, P&G membership proposal
    - NAPNAP - Procter & Gamble Projects June - December 1989 (Box-folder 010-011)
      Re: Seal of approval for Pampers, response from NAPNAP members, preparation of booklets on diaper rash and on the environment
    - Carnation Company: Projects August - November 1989 (Box-folder 010-012)
      Re: Breastfeeding versus formula and Carnation products
    - NANP: Correspondence and Related Documents January - May 1989 (Box-folder 010-013)
      Re: National Alliance of Nurse Practitioners, National Building of Nursing Specialties
    - NAPNAP Foundation February - December 1989 (Box-folder 010-014)
      Re: Research grant awards, report on research, applications, budget
    - Capitol Association about ABC Child Care Bills July - November 1989 (Box-folder 010-015)
      Re: Legislation on child care
    - Capitol Association on AIDS August - December 1989 (Box-folder 010-016)
      Re: Awards to RNs, funding for personnel to care for AIDS patients
    - Capitol Association: Miscellaneous issues July - October 1989 (Box-folder 010-017)
      Re: Boy Scout physical examination, children's television legislation, infant mortality commission, and minority health
    - Capitol Association: Miscellaneous issues August - October 1989 (Box-folder 010-018)
      Re: Federal employees' health benefits, foreign nurses, malpractice insurance reform
    - Capitol Associates, Pepper Commission June - December 1989 (Box-folder 011-001)
      Re: Access to long term care
    - Capitol Associates, Miscellaneous issues February - September 1989 (Box-folder 011-002)
      Re: National Center for Nursing Research funding, National Commission on Children, National health Service Corps
    - Capitol Associates, Miscellaneous issues June - December 1989 (Box-folder 011-003)
      Re: NP databank, Nurses Coalition for Legislative action, nursing education legislation, third party reimbursement, vaccine advisory committee
    - Capitol Associates, Miscellaneous issues January - December 1989 (Box-folder 011-004)
      Re: Miscellaneous legislative issues affecting NPs
    - President Millonig: Correspondence January - March 1990 (Box-folder 011-005)
      Re: Miscellaneous NAPNAP business, endorsement of disposable diapers, meeting planning, legislation affecting PNPs, certificates for NAPNAP service
    - President Millonig: Correspondence April - June 1990 (Box-folder 011-006)
      Re: Miscellaneous NAPNAP business, brochure on diaper rash, chapters communication problems, NAPNAP foundation
    - President Mullins: Correspondence July - September 1990 (Box-folder 011-007)
    - President Mullins: Correspondence October - December 1990 (Box-folder 011-008)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, chapter relations, legislation affecting PNPs
    - Past President Millonig: Correspondence July - November 1990 (Box-folder 011-009)
      Re: NAPNAP seal of approval, corporate relations
    - Executive Director, McGuire, M.: Correspondence January - March 1990 (Box-folder 011-010)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, legislation, board meeting, PNP schools, corporate relations, certification, Congressional testimony
    - Executive Director, McGuire, M: Correspondence April - June 1990 (Box-folder 011-011)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, policy and position statement report, childcare programs - NAPNAP position
    - Executive Director, McGuire, M: Correspondence July - August 1990 (Box-folder 011-012)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, NAPNAP Foundation bylaws, President's schedule, AMA report on independent nursing practice, royalties, finances, standards of practice, National Board of Nursing Specialties
    - Executive Director, McGuire, M: Correspondence September - December 1990 (Box-folder 011-013)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, corporate grants, finances and audit, delegates to organization, NP privileges, oral rehydration therapy (ORT) project
    - Director of Membership and Communications: Correspondence January - March 1990 (Box-folder 011-014)
      Re: PR, chapter relations, press releases, 25th anniversary of PNP movement, newsletter
    - Director of Membership and Communications: Correspondence April - December 1990 (Box-folder 011-015)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, 1990 - 1991 activities, chapter communications, grants available, National Safe Kids campaign
    - Executive secretary; National Office Manager January - December 1990 (Box-folder 011-016)
      Re: Miscellaneous NAPNAP business, history, membership, board and staff members and chapter contracts, PNP school list, use of NAPNAP membership list, conference contest winners
    - Members and sustaining members July - December 1990 (Box-folder 012-001)
      Re: Membership statistics and sustaining members
    - Budget and Financial statement August - November 1990 (Box-folder 012-002)
      Re: Budget and Financial statement
    - Membership Mailings April - July 1990 (Box-folder 012-003)
      Re: Form letters to membership, Proctor and Gamble sponsorship of membership for new PNP graduates
    - Ketchum: Public Relations Report October 12, 1990 (Box-folder 012-004)
      Re: Recommendations for NAPNAP PR efforts, 1990 - 1991
    - Long Range Planning Committee January - December 1990 (Box-folder 012-005)
      Re: 1990 long range planning process and documents
    - By-laws Committee February - April 1990 (Box-folder 012-006)
      Re: By-laws revision
    - Nominations Committee Chair: Correspondence January - December 1990 (Box-folder 012-007)
      Re: 1990 - 1991 elections
    - Legislation Committee: Correspondence February - May 1990 (Box-folder 012-008)
      Re: Family and Medical Leave Act, insuring children, legislative update, Texas Nurse Practice Act
    - Continuing Education Committee, Program Committee: Correspondence March - December 1990 (Box-folder 012-009)
      Re: Conference programming, continuing education report
    - PR and Publications Committee: Correspondence January - November 1990 (Box-folder 012-010)
      Re: Committee members, statement of AIDs, NAPNAP slide bank
    - NAPNAP Task Force: Breastfeeding June - September 1990 (Box-folder 012-011)
      Re: Joan Greene's participation in USDA breastfeeding promotion program
    - Medicaid Task Force: Correspondence July - October 1990 (Box-folder 012-012)
      Re: Medicaid reimbursement legislation
    - McNeil Scholarship January - December 1990 (Box-folder 012-013)
      Re: Procedures, winners
    - Grant-In-Aid Program January - May 1990 (Box-folder 012-014)
      Re: 1990 Recipients, conference evaluations
    - Journal of Pediatric Health Care/ Mosby February - December 1990 (Box-folder 012-015)
      Re: Editorial Board Meetings on journal, financial statement, and correspondence with Mosby Co.
    - Corporate Projects: NAPNAP/ Mennen January - September 1990 (Box-folder 012-016)
      Re: March of Dimes Walk, Mennen Baby Magic (NAPNAP seal)
    - Corporate Projects: Procter & Gamble/ NAPNAP January - October 1990 (Box-folder 012-017)
      Re: Disposable diapers, includes NAPNAP members' response to issue, Procter and Gamble report on solid waste
    - Corporate Projects: Ross, Sandoz, Lehn & Fink February - September 1990 (Box-folder 013-001)
      Re: Telephone management project, Ross sponsorship of NAPNAP newsletter, review of Lysol product for NAPNAP Seal of Acceptance
    - McGuire-Woods NAPNAP Correspondence February 1990 (Box-folder 013-002)
      Re: Johnsen v. School District (NAPNAP amicus brief)
    - Associations: ANA, AAP/ NAPNAP Correspondence July - December 1990 (Box-folder 013-003)
      Re: NAPNAP input on nursing issues; NAPNAP participation in committees on school health, community health, ANA standards of practice task force
    - Associations: NANP/ NAPNAP Correspondence April - November 1990 (Box-folder 013-004)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in National Alliance of Nurse Practitioners, mostly legislative issues, including DEA regulations about NPs
    - Associations: NOLF/ NAPNAP Correspondence January - August 1990 (Box-folder 013-005)
      Re: NAPNAP participation in ANA's Nursing Organization Liaison Forum
    - NAPNAP Foundation January - December 1990 (Box-folder 013-006)
      Re: Research grants, reports and correspondence
    - NAPNAP Foundation January - November 1990 (Box-folder 013-007)
      Re: Application review, elections to board, finances and contributions by Procter and Gamble, individuals
    - Capitol Associates: ABC Child Care Legislation January - November 1990 (Box-folder 013-008)
      Re: Child care legislation, Alliance for Better Childcare
    - Capitol Associates: AHCPR February - December 1990 (Box-folder 013-009)
      Re: Agency for Health Care Policy and Research, formation and activities, effect on nursing
    - Capitol Associates: Access to Care, AIDS February - December 1990 (Box-folder 013-010)
      Re: Various legislative issues on access to care, practice guidelines for personnel with HIV
    - Capitol Associates: Children's Issues March - November 1990 (Box-folder 013-011)
      Re: Children's television legislation and programming, National Commission on Infant Mortality Education Consortium, Disadvantaged Children Act, safety restraints in aircraft, fetal alcohol syndrome, Crime Control Act, Child Health Day, lead poisoning, pediatric emergency seizures, consumer product safety
    - Capitol Associates: Family and Medical Leave Act January - December 1990 (Box-folder 013-012)
      Re: Family Medical Leave legislation
    - Capitol Associates: FEHBP January - October 1990 (Box-folder 013-013)
      Re: Legislation to include nurses in direct reimbursement under Federal Employees Health Benefits Program, includes NAPNAP testimony to Congress
    - Capitol Associates: Medicaid, Malpractice, Minority Health February - August 1990 (Box-folder 013-014)
      Re: Hatch Malpractice Bill on liability reform, direct Medicaid reimbursements to PNPs, changes in Medicaid coverage, Minority health needs
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous January - July 1990 (Box-folder 014-001)
      Re: Miscellaneous issues, including National Commission on Children, National Health Education Consortium, National Health Services Corps, National Institute of Child Health and Human Development Coalition
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous January - March 1990 (Box-folder 014-002)
      Re: Miscellaneous legislative issues, including preventative health initiative, Hill Nurses' Caucus, CDC appropriations, Universal Health Bill, National Institute of Mental Health funding
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous April - June 1990 (Box-folder 014-003)
      Re: Miscellaneous legislative issues, including grant funds, media images of nurses, RCTs, physician recertification, meeting with Representative Boxer, expanding health insurance, WIC/ infant formula prices
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous July - September 1990 (Box-folder 014-004)
      Re: Miscellaneous funds, faculty fellowship program, community nursing organization demonstrations, women's health care coverage expansion act, RCTs, urban health care delivery
    - Capitol Associates: Miscellaneous October - December 1990 (Box-folder 014-005)
      Re: Miscellaneous legislative issues, including grant funding, WIC program/ infant formula, Women's Health Equity Act, women's health issues, Drug Enforcement Agency working group, Agency for International Development
    - Capitol Associates: National Practitioner Data Bank, Nursing Shortage January - December 1990 (Box-folder 014-006)
      Re: Tracking malpractice actions, commission on national nursing shortage
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Research January - November 1990 (Box-folder 014-007)
      Re: National Center for Nursing Research, NCNR Advisory Council, National Institutes of Health, Center for Disease Control, research funding
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Education January - May 1990 (Box-folder 014-008)
      Re: Mostly funding for nursing education, includes NAPNAP testimony to Congress, Advisory Council on Nurse Education, PNP educational programs data
    - Capitol Associates: Nursing Education June - December 1990 (Box-folder 014-009)
      Re: Mostly funding for nursing education, includes: reauthorization of Nurse Training Act (pending), Indian health Service grants, Advisory Council on Nurse Education, PNP Education survey
    - Capitol Associates: Rural Health February - December 1990 (Box-folder 014-010)
      Re: Incentives for NPs to practice in rural areas, testimony by NP to Senators, Rural Nursing Incentive Act
    - Capitol Associates: Vaccines April - December 1990 (Box-folder 014-011)
      Re: Advisory Committee on Childhood Vaccines, legislation on vaccines
    - Capitol Associates: Pepper Commission, Prospective Payment Assessment Commission February - October 1990 (Box-folder 015-001)
      Re: Health care legislation, cost factors associated with non-physician healthcare providers
    - Capitol Associates: Physician Payment Review Commission January - December 1990 (Box-folder 015-002)
      Re: Payment to non-physician providers
    - President Ruth Mullins: Correspondence January - April 1991 (Box-folder 015-003)
      Re: Miscellaneous business, including Congressional testimony, meeting planning, information on PNPs for National Health Service Corps white paper, NAPNAP bylaw changes, inclusion of NPs on Immunization Bill, opposition to NCB PNP/N on certificate issue, NAPNAP staff analysis, computer committees
    - President Ruth Mullins: Correspondence May - November 1991 (Box-folder 015-004)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including NAPNAP position on ANA health care document, nominations to commissions, meeting planning, Congressional testimony, Capitol Associates information, committee assignments, NAPNAP Foundation management, NAPNAP disagreement with NCP about certificate coverage
    - President Ellen Clore: Correspondence January - December 1991 (Box-folder 015-005)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including: invitations to conferences declined, President's letter to members on "State of NAPNAP," goals/ objectives of NAPNAP Committees, endorsement for Family Leave Act, endorsement of child-resistent drug packaging and other child safety initiatives, child welfare initiatives, nominations of NAPNAP members to advisory boards, opposition to NAPNAP promotion of products from members, NAPNAP opposition to Gag Rule, Support of CDC on HIV recommendations
    - Past President V. Millonig: Correspondence February - July 1991 (Box-folder 015-006)
      Re: Miscellaneous, including past president's activities, past president's council meeting, NAPNAP response to ANA statement on practice standards, Millonig past president report
    - President Clore: Annual Letter to Members July 1991 (Box-folder 015-007)
      Re: NAPNAP activities in 1990 - 1991, planned activities for 1991 - 1992, annual report 1990 - 1991
    - President-Elect Margaret Grey: Correspondence April - December 1991 (Box-folder 015-008)
      Re: Promotion of primary care research, NAPNAP endorsement of ANA health care reform plan, bylaws committee, bylaws changes
    - Executive Director Mavis McGuire: Correspondence February - June 1991 (Box-folder 015-009)